♪I lament on the cruel and untimely love♪
أنا أتحسر على الحب القاسي والغير أوانه ♪
♪Yet I come to realise it's a daydream when the bubbles burst♪
♪ ومع ذلك أدركت أنه حلم يقظة عندما تنفجر الفقاعات ♪
♪A city of spring flowers♪
♪ مدينة زهور الربيع ♪
♪Sinks into the indifferent autumnal frost♪
♪ يغرق في الصقيع الخريفي غير المبال
♪A snowflake falls into the river♪
♪ تسقط ندفة ثلجية في النهر ♪
♪The biting cold stalks over♪
♪ البرد القارص ينبع
♪All assumptions are nothing♪
كل الافتراضات لا شيء
♪But a disguised makeup♪
♪ لكن مكياج مقنع
♪I bid farewell♪
أودع
♪To the passionate gaze behind the mask♪
♪ للنظرة العاطفية خلف القناع ♪
♪Love and hate are the most unforgettable feelings♪
الحب والكراهية من أكثر المشاعر التي لا تنسى
♪Overwhelmed by my longings♪
غارقة في شوقي ♪
♪I tear off those old scores♪
♪ مزقت تلك الدرجات القديمة ♪
♪I bid farewell♪
أودع
♪To the irretrievable past♪
إلى الماضي الذي لا يمكن استرجاعه ♪
=Little Mad Doctor=
= الطبيب المجنون الصغير =
=Episode 16=
= الحلقة 16 =
Chu Jinghong.
تشو جينغهونغ.
Is Northern Chu a poor state?
هل شمال تشو دولة فقيرة؟
Presenting a plant as a birthday gift?
تقديم نبات كهدية عيد ميلاد؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
This is
هذا هو
the Queen of the Night.
ملكة الليل.
The legend has it
الأسطورة لديها ذلك
that whoever
هذا أيا كان
is able
قادر
to let it bloom,
للسماح لها بالازدهار ،
the person will
الشخص سوف
bring great fortune to the empire.
جلب ثروة كبيرة للإمبراطورية.
Empress.
الإمبراطورة.
Why don't you give it a try?
لماذا لا تجربها؟
It doesn't matter
لا يهم
whether the flower blooms or not.
سواء كانت الزهرة تزهر أم لا.
Well, I shall try it.
حسنًا ، سأحاول ذلك.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Consider it a pleasant interlude.
اعتبرها فترة فاصلة ممتعة.
(Darned Chu Jinghong.)
(مرهق تشو جينغهونغ.)
(Do you mean I don't deserve to be the empress)
(هل تقصد أنني لا أستحق أن أكون الإمبراطورة)
(if the flowers don't bloom?)
(إذا لم تتفتح الأزهار؟)
You shall bloom now.
سوف تتفتح الآن.
For the perpetual prosperity
من أجل الازدهار الدائم
of the Shang Empire.
من إمبراطورية شانغ.
(What's going on?)
(ماذا يحدث هنا؟)
(Come on.)
(تعال.)
It seems the blooming
يبدو أنها تتفتح
that brings prosperity to the empire
التي تجلب الرخاء للإمبراطورية
is but a legend.
ما هو إلا أسطورة.
No, no.
لا لا.
Since Princess Jinghong is confident about this legend,
بما أن الأميرة جينغ هونغ واثقة من هذه الأسطورة ،
why don't you try this?
لماذا لا تجرب هذا
Bloom now.
ازهر الآن.
Look, the flowers bloom.
انظروا ، الزهور تتفتح.
They're blooming.
إنهم يزهرون.
How beautiful.
كم هو جميل.
This is amazing.
هذا مذهل.
(Chu Jinghong.)
(تشو جينغهونغ.)
(Do you purposely embarrass me?)
(هل تحرجني عمدا؟)
(Why is it happening now? It's not the time yet.)
(لماذا يحدث ذلك الآن؟ لم يحن الوقت بعد.)
(Is something wrong with the liquor earlier?)
(هل هناك خطأ ما في الخمور في وقت سابق؟)
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Since the bloom happened,
منذ حدوث الإزهار ،
I shall
على أن
take my leave now.
خذ إجازتي الآن.
Hold still.
اثبت.
Are you forcing me to stay?
هل تجبرني على البقاء؟
I shall see
سأرى
who's going to get in my way.
من سيقف في طريقي.
Longyuan.
لونجيوان.
I understand you don't intend to murder for drinking human blood.
أفهم أنك لا تنوي القتل لشربك دم بشري.
I
أنا
won't let you pay
لن يسمح لك بالدفع
with your life.
مع حياتك.
However,
لكن،
you're a dangerous threat
أنت تهديد خطير
to Shang.
إلى Shang.
What has Lord War got to do with the murder?
ما علاقة Lord War بالقتل؟
Alas.
واحسرتاه.
How unfortunate.
يالسوء الحظ.
Though Longyuan fought enemies to bring peace to the empire,
على الرغم من أن لونجيوان حارب الأعداء لإحلال السلام في الإمبراطورية ،
he was attacked by the Blood Curse during the war.
تعرض لهجوم من قبل لعنة الدم خلال الحرب.
The Blood Curse
لعنة الدم
is grotesque
بشع
as the cursed
مثل الملعون
needs human blood
يحتاج إلى دم بشري
to sustain their lives.
للحفاظ على حياتهم.
I know Longyuan did this out of despair.
أعلم أن لونجيوان فعل ذلك بدافع اليأس.
But
لكن
I can't allow you
لا استطيع السماح لك
to slaughter my people.
لذبح شعبي.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Where did you hear this from?
أين سمعت هذا من؟
You've been deceived.
لقد تم خداعك.
You accuse me of being the murderer,
أنت تتهمني بأنني القاتل ،
can you prove it?
هل تستطيع اثبات ذلك؟
Those afflicted with the Blood Curse
أصابهم لعنة الدم
bleeds from every pore
ينزف من كل مسام
during the full-moon night.
خلال ليلة اكتمال القمر.
Do you dare
هل تجرؤ
remove your clothes
اخلعي ​​ملابسك
and prove yourself?
وتثبت نفسك؟
If you said so.
إذا قلت ذلك.
No blood stains on him.
لا بقع دم عليه.
What's happening now?
ماذا يحدث الان؟
I told you so.
قلت لك ذلك.
Lord War can't be the murderer.
لورد وور لا يمكن أن يكون القاتل.
Lord War isn't that kind of person.
Lord War ليس هذا النوع من الأشخاص.
He wouldn't kill for his own sake.
لن يقتل من أجل مصلحته.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
The real culprit
الجاني الحقيقي
has already been captured by Lord War.
تم الاستيلاء عليها بالفعل من قبل Lord War.
We intended to report this.
كنا نعتزم الإبلاغ عن هذا.
However, it's ominous
ومع ذلك ، هذا أمر ينذر بالسوء
to announce this
للإعلان عن هذا
during your birthday banquet.
خلال مأدبة عيد ميلادك.
The culprit
الجاني
used these three hollowed needles coated with blood thinners
تستخدم هذه الإبر المجوفة الثلاث المغلفة بمخففات الدم
to drain the victims' blood.
لاستنزاف دماء الضحايا.
Regarding this,
بخصوص هذا ،
Director Ye and I have found the truth.
المخرج يي وأنا وجدنا الحقيقة.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
The serial killer was found
تم العثور على القاتل المتسلسل
and he confessed to his crime.
واعترف بجريمته.
This is the statement.
هذا هو البيان.
I shall take my leave.
سوف آخذ إجازتي.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
May I go now?
هل يمكني الذهاب الان؟
Hyah!
Hyah!
My Lord.
ربي.
Are you all right, My Lord?
هل أنت بخير يا ربي؟
Are you fine, My Lord?
هل انت بخير ربي؟
(I must concoct the antidote as soon as possible.)
(يجب أن أقوم بتلفيق الترياق في أسرع وقت ممكن).
How come the Blood Curse in Yu Longyuan
كيف تأتي لعنة الدم في Yu Longyuan
didn't flare up just now?
لم تشتعل الآن؟
Well...
حسنًا...
I did add the substance
لقد أضفت الجوهر
that triggers the Blood Curse in his drink.
تسبب لعنة الدم في شرابه.
Has he
له انه
found the method to break the poison?
وجدت طريقة لكسر السم؟
Break the poison?
كسر السم؟
Didn't you say
لم تقل
this poison is hard to cure?
هذا السم يصعب علاجه؟
Perhaps
ربما
they only got to alleviate the pain.
ما عليهم إلا أن يخففوا الألم.
Second Prince.
الأمير الثاني.
What's bothering you?
ما الذي يزعجك؟
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
I know you're annoyed
أعلم أنك منزعج
because of Chu Jinghong and Lord War.
بسبب Chu Jinghong و Lord War.
They are deeply in love now.
إنهم مغرمون بعمق الآن.
It's difficult
انه صعب
to separate them.
لفصلهم.
But...
لكن...
What's it?
ما هذا؟
But I have an idea.
لكن لدي فكرة.
This is so fun.
هذا ممتع جدا.
Oh?
أوه؟
Where's Jin'er?
أين جينير؟
Well.
حسنًا.
She said the weather has grown colder.
قالت إن الطقس أصبح أكثر برودة.
She returned to Suoqing Palace
عادت إلى قصر Suoqing
to fetch some thick clothes.
لجلب بعض الملابس السميكة.
Please forgive me.
رجائاً أعطني.
I wasn't paying attention and accidentally bumped into you.
لم أكن منتبها واصطدمت بك عن طريق الخطأ.
Please spare me, Your Highness.
أرجوك أنقذني يا صاحب السمو.
Why are you calling me Your Highness
لماذا تتصل بي صاحب السمو
when you didn't even look at me?
عندما لم تنظر إلي حتى؟
What if
ماذا إذا
I'm a lowly person?
أنا شخص متواضع؟
Lowly...person?
متواضع ... شخص؟
♪I sigh at my life♪
♪ أنا أتنهد في حياتي ♪
♪There's nowhere to anchor on shore♪
♪ لا يوجد مكان للرسو على الشاطئ
♪Nothing to cherish in the world♪
لا شيء نعتز به في العالم
♪Except for you♪
ما عداك ♪
♪The past we've been through retains♪
♪ الماضي الذي مررنا به
♪Even though time wears thin♪
على الرغم من أن الوقت يضعف ♪
♪The thought of being together lifelong♪
فكرة البقاء معًا مدى الحياة
♪Exists beyond time♪
موجود خارج الزمن ♪
♪All joys and sorrows♪
♪ كل افراح و احزان ♪
♪Reflect in your gentle gaze♪
انعكس في نظراتك اللطيفة
♪I will spend my life waiting♪
♪ سأقضي حياتي في الانتظار ♪
♪For the chance to be forever by your side♪
للحصول على فرصة أن تكون بجانبك إلى الأبد
♪Hair turns grey in one winter night♪
♪ يتحول لون الشعر إلى اللون الرمادي في ليلة شتاء ♪
♪The appearance remains in spite of the thick frost♪
المظهر يبقى بالرغم من الصقيع الكثيف
♪Time slips by in that dream-like world♪
♪ الوقت يمر في هذا العالم الذي يشبه الحلم
♪Life is always full of splendor♪
♪ الحياة دائما مليئة بالروعة
♪We part when the flowers fall♪
♪ نفترق عندما تسقط الأزهار
♪Desolate chills blow away several autumns♪
♪ قشعريرة مقفرة تهب عدة خريفات ♪
♪Eternal love is all I seek♪
الحب الأبدي هو كل ما أسعى إليه
♪Though the sweet dream fades at last♪
رغم أن الحلم الجميل يتلاشى أخيرًا ♪
♪I sigh at my life♪
♪ أنا أتنهد في حياتي ♪
♪There's nowhere to anchor on shore♪
♪ لا يوجد مكان للرسو على الشاطئ
♪Nothing to cherish in the world♪
لا شيء نعتز به في العالم
♪Except for you♪
ما عداك ♪
♪The past we've been through retains♪
♪ الماضي الذي مررنا به
♪Even though time wears thin♪
على الرغم من أن الوقت يضعف ♪
♪The thought of being together lifelong♪
فكرة البقاء معًا مدى الحياة
♪Exists beyond time♪
موجود خارج الزمن ♪
♪All joys and sorrows♪
♪ كل افراح و احزان ♪
♪Reflect in your gentle gaze♪
انعكس في نظراتك اللطيفة
♪I will spend my life waiting♪
♪ سأقضي حياتي في الانتظار ♪
♪For the chance to be forever by your side♪
للحصول على فرصة أن تكون بجانبك إلى الأبد